A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, Mexico, RG 6, SG 13 FA398
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, field offices, Mexico, RG 6, SG 13
1943-1965
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
Rockefeller Foundation. Mexico
FA398
26.98 Cubic Feet 70 letter document boxes, 2 half-letter document boxes.
Other Finding Aids note
Other available finding aids describing Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices include:
FA395 Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, Paris.
FA396 Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, New Delhi, India.
FA397 Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Offices, Cali, Colombia.
FA399 Rockefeller Foundation records, Field Office, Ankara, Turkey.
File Plan note
RG 6.13.
Organization of the Foundation's archives:
RG 1 Projects
RG 2 General Correspondence
RG 3 Administration, Program and Policy
RG 4 China Medical Board
RG 5 International Health Board/Division
RG 6 Field Offices
RG 7 Treasurer's Office
RG 8 Comptroller
RG 9 Personnel
RG 10 Fellowships
RG 11 Information Services
RG 12 Diaries
RG 13 Oral Histories
RG 14 Counsel
RG 15 Secretary
RG 16 Minutes and Officers Actions
RG 17 Dockets
RG 18 Declinations (100F)
RG 19 Non-textual Materials
RG 20 Communications Office.
Biographical/Historical note
In 1943, the Rockefeller Foundation and the Mexican government established a cooperative program to improve Mexican food crop production. The program had a dual nature: the qualitative/quantitative betterment of the basic food crops of Mexico, and a parallel teaching/outreach program designed to broaden local and national agricultural education. As a result the RF and Mexican government agencies and universities sponsored dozens of joint projects that stressed inter-American agricultural cooperation. Crop improvement programs for maize, wheat, and rice were included, as well as weed control and fisheries projects.
Scope and Contents note
The records include correspondence, conference proceedings, financial materials, annual reports, fellowships material, officers diaries, and personnel records.
Arrangement note
Series 1.1 - General Office Files, 1943-1965; Series 1.2 - Experimental Camp Files, 1943-1965.
Related Archival Materials note
Photographs from these files are located in the Rockefeller Foundation photograph collection.
Conditions Governing Access note
Records more than 20 years old are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Agricultural innovations; Agricultural innovations -- Mexico; Medical sciences; Medical research -- India; Social sciences -- India; Public health; India; Latin America; Colombia; Green Revolution; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Charities; Agriculture; Agriculture -- India; Philanthropy; Medical education; Life sciences; Medical research; Philanthropy -- United States
- General Office Files, 1943-1965; 1
  - Abin, Leonardo - 1959-1961 Acosta, Ricardo - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adriance, Guy - (Texas A&M University), 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Africa-Cooperative Maize Programs - 1959-1960 Africa-General - 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Economics, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Education, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Education, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Agricultural Education Extension Service, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Engineering, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Improvement for the Far East, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Information-INIA - 1962 Agricultural Research - 1955-1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aguascalientes, State of - 1959 Air Conditioning Equipment - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alliance for Progress, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - American Chamber of Commerce of Mexico, 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - American Embassy, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Genetic Association - 1960 American Men of Science - 1961 American Phytopathological Society - 1960-1962 American Seed Trade Assocation - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Society for Horticultural Science - 1957-1961 American Society of Agronomy - 1958-1962 American Society of Mexico - 1960 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Anderson, Edgar - 1959-1962 Angola - 1961, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Animal Husbandry Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Animal Science, 1959-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1943-1961 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Annual Reports (MAP), 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Annual Reports (MAP) - Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Annual Reports (MAP) - Manuscripts, 1961-1962 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Anthropology - (National Institute of Anthropology and History), 1939-1951 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Anthropology - (National Institute of Anthropology and History), 1939-1951 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Anthropology - (National Institute of Anthropology and History), 1939-1951 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Arena, Antonio (Uruguay), 1953 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Argentina, 1950, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Argentina, 1950, 1956-1962 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Argentina - Libros de Campo, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Arrieta, Dario L. (Direccion de Agricultura), 1943-1946 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Asia - 1961 Asociacion Mexicana de Rehabilitacion - 1960 Associated Colleges of the Midwest - 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Astralaga, Roberto (Colombia-Fellow) - 1948-1950 Auchter, E.C. (USDA) - Report: United States and Mexico Agricultural Cooperation - 1946 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Aughtry, J.D. (Dominican Republic) - 1953 Australia - 1962 Austria - 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Baird, Guy B. (RF-Colombia), 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Baja California, State of, 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Banks, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Barley Program (FAO/UN and OEE), 1954-1960 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Barnes, Douglas, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Bean Breeding Program - Bean Trials, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Bean Breeding Program - General Reports, 1945-1960 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Bean Breeding Program - General Reports, 1945-1960 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Bean Breeding Program - Munoz (Jose M.) Report, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Belgian Congo - 1959-1962 Bolivia - 1956-1962 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Bonnet, Juan A. (Puerto Rico) - 1953 Boothroyd, C.W. (Cornell University) - 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Borlaug, Norman E. Correspondence - 1959-1962 Report: South America Trip - 1952 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Botany Reports - 1958 Boyce, A.M. - Diary: Latin America Trip - 1959 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Bradfield, Richard (Cornell University) - 1960-1962 Brauer, Oscar (Germany) - 1960-1961 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Brazil - Comite Panamericano Coordinador De Congresos De Ciencias Agricolas, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Brazil - General Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Brazil - General Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Brazil - General Correspondence, 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Brazil - Libros De Campo, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Brennan and Co. (Laredo, Texas), 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Brennan and Co. (Laredo, Texas), 1957-1962 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - British Guiana - 1959-1962 British Honduras - 1956-1959 British West Indies - 1961, 1956-1962 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Brown, William - 1959-1962 Buller, Roderic E. (Venezuela) - 1962 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Cacao, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - California - 1960-1962 California, University of - 1959-1960, 1959-1962 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Cambodia - 1960-1961 Campeche, State of - 1954-1961 Canada - 1960-1962 Candia, Daniel (Cornell University) - 1962, 1954-1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Carballo, Alfredo (Costa Rica), 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Carballo, Alfredo (Costa Rica), 1954-1956 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Casseres, Ernest (IIAS/OAS) - 1961-1963 Castillo, Jorge (Mexico) - 1960-1962, 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Annual Reports, 1954-1958 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Corn Improvement Meeting - Program, March 9-13, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Corn Improvement Meeting - Reports, March 9-13, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Corn Improvement Meeting - Reports, March 9-13, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Corn Tests, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Costa Rica Carballo, Alfredo - 1954-1958 General Correspondence - 1953-1958 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project El Salvador - 1954-1958 Guatemala - 1954-1958 Honduras - 1954-1958 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Instructions, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Mailing Lists, 1958-1964 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - News Bulletins, 1957-1958 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project Nicaragua - 1953-1958 Panama - 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Program Outline, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Randomizations and Field Books, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Randomizations and Field Books, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Randomizations and Field Books, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Randomizations and Field Books, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Seed Shipments, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Smith, Donald L. - Correspondence and Diary, 1954-1958 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project Special Recommendations - 1961 Supplies - 1960, 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Uniform Yield Tests, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Uniform Yield Tests, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Uniform Yield Tests, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Uniform Yield Tests, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Uniform Yield Tests, 1954, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Central American Corn Improvement Project - Wortman, Sterling - Correspondence and Diary, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Central American Nutrition Institute - 1946 Ceylon - 1961-1962 Chase, Sherret S. (Illinois) - 1961 (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Chemical Products, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Chiapas, State of, 1954-1961 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Chihuahua, State of, 1954-1962 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Chile, 1958-1962 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Chilean Agricultural Program - Correspondence, 1955-1961 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Chilean Agricultural Program - Reports, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - China (Taiwan) - 1962 Chopra, Kuldip Raj - 1961-1962 Christenson, Clyde M. - 1962 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Ciudad Obregon, Sonora - 1959-1962 Clima Control, S.A. - 1962 (Box 8, Folder 102)
  - Coahuila, State of, 1949-1962 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Cockerham, C. Clyde - 1961 Colima, State of - 1955-1960 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - Colleges and Universities - United States, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Colleges and Universities - United States, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Colombia "El Rubi" Experiment Station - 1951-1952 Facultad de Agronomia (Medellin) - 1947-1952 Facultad de Agronomia del Valle (Palmira) - 1958-1950, 1951-1958 (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Colombia - General Correspondence, 1949-1962 (Box 9, Folder 108)
  - Colombia - General Correspondence, 1949-1962 (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Colombia - General Correspondence, 1949-1962 (Box 9, Folder 110)
  - Colombia Hawkes, John J. (Potato Collections) - 1946-1950 I.A.I.P. - 1959, 1946-1959 (Box 9, Folder 111)
  - Colombia Libros de Campo - 1960 Minister of Agriculture - 1947-1951 Navas Pardo, Don Pedro - 1950-1951, 1947-1960 (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Colombia Reports - 1953, 1960 Second Andean Corn Meeting - 1961-1962, 1953-1962 (Box 9, Folder 113)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program - Annual Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 114)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program - Annual Reports, 1951-1953 (Box 9, Folder 115)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program - General Correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box 9, Folder 116)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program - General Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program Mejia Velez, Eduardo - 1947-1951 Ortiz Mendez, Jorge - 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program - Progress Reports and Proposals, 1947-1951 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Colombian Agricultural Program Roberts, Lewis M. - 1950-1955 Rupert, J.A. - 1952-1955 (Box 10, Folder 120)
  - Colorado - 1954, 1961 Comision del Papaloapan - 1951-1954 Comision Internacional de Plagas - 1942, 1942-1961 (Box 10, Folder 121)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Annual Reports, 1952-1954, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 122)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Annual Reports, 1952-1954, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 123)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Annual Reports, 1952-1954, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 124)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Decree, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 125)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - General Correspondence, 1947-1961 (Box 10, Folder 126)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - General Correspondence, 1947-1961 (Box 10, Folder 127)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Ochoa, Rogelio Espinosa, 1951-1956 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Comision Nacional del Maiz - Reports, 1948-1961 (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - Comision para determinar Posibilidados del Cultivo del Trigo en San Lois Potos, S.L.P., 1954 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Comite Calificador de Variedades de Plantas, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - Comite para la Multiplicacion Y Propagacion de Semillas Mejoradas- Ambrosio, Antonio Marino - 1948 Cantero, Benjamin Ortega - 1947-1951 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - Comite para la Multiplicacion Y Propagacion de Semillas Mejoradas - General Correspondence, 1948-1953 (Box 11, Folder 133)
  - Committee on Integration of Research, Education and Extension - 1961-1962 Comstock, R.E. - 1959-1960, 1959-1962 (Box 11, Folder 134)
  - Confederacion Patronal de la Republica Mexicana - 1960-1961 Consejo Tecnio Mexicano para la Conservacion de Granos - (n.d.) Consulates - General Correspondence - 1959-1960, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 135)
  - Corn Breeding (OEE) - Reports, 1948-1959 (Box 11, Folder 136)
  - Corn Collection Program/Mexico and Central America - 1952-1955 Corn Diseases - 1959 Corn Germ Plasm - 1956-1959, 1952-1959 (Box 11, Folder 137)
  - Corn Improvement Program - Conferences, 1954, 1956, 1958, 1960-1962 (Box 11, Folder 138)
  - Corn Improvement Program - Proposal (Marte R. Gomez), 1944 (Box 11, Folder 139)
  - Corn Improvement Program - Reports, 1943-1959 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Corn Papers - E.J. Wellhausen, 1953-1960 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - Corn Reports, 1943-1962 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - Corn Reports, 1943-1962 (Box 12, Folder 143)
  - Corn Reports - Chromosomes - 1961 Corn Stunt Virus in Central America and Colombia - 1958 Corn Yield Tests - 1955-1956, 1955-1961 (Box 12, Folder 144)
  - Cornell University - 1958-1961 Corns, J.B. - 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 145)
  - Costa Rica - Central American Corn Improvement Project, 1956, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 146)
  - Costa Rica - Central American Corn Improvement Project, 1956, 1958 (Box 12, Folder 147)
  - Costa Rica - Central American Corn Improvement Project, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Costa Rica - Ensayos, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Costa Rica - General Correspondence, 1953-1955, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - Costa Rica - General Correspondence, 1953-1955, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Costa Rica - General Correspondence, 1953-1955, 1958-1962 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - Costa Rica - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas, 1945-1962 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Costa Rica - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas, 1945-1962 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - Costa Rica - Instituto Interamericano de Ciencias Agricolas, 1945-1962 (Box 13, Folder 155)
  - Costa Rica - Reports, 1953, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - Costa Rica - Smith, Donald L., 1957 (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - Covarrubias, Ramon - 1959 Cogwill, Ursula M. - 1960, 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - Crop Quality Control Council (Minnesota) - 1961-1962 Crop Science Society of America - 1961-1962 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - Cuba General Correspondence - 1954-1961 Kevorkian, Arthur G. - 1946-1949, 1946-1961 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - Customs - 1962 Czechoslovakia - 1959-1960 (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Daza, Pablo E. - 1959-1960 DeKalb Agricultural Association, Inc. - 1961 De Lara Tours S.A. Mexico - 1961 Del Valle, C.G. (Florida) - 1960, 1959-1961 (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Denys, Gustavo (El Salvador) - 1958 Department of Transportation (Mexico) - 1943-1956 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - Derriengue, 1942-1945 (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - Development of Tropical Center (Chipas & Tabasco) - 1962 Diagnostic Laboratory (Chapingo) - 1958, 1958-1962 (Box 14, Folder 165)
  - Direccion de Conservacion del Suelo y el Agua (SAG) - 1946-1950 Direccion de Economia Rural (SAG) - 1955-1956 Direccion General de Aduanas - 1961-1962, 1946-1962 (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Agricultural Extension Service - Agents, 1948-1949 (Box 14, Folder 167)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Agricultural Extension Service - General Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Agricultural Extension Service - General Correspondence, 1953-1961 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - General Correspondence, 1946-1962 (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - General Correspondence, 1946-1962 (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Plantings, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Wheat Department, 1957-1960 (Box 15, Folder 173)
  - Direccion General de Agricultura - Wheat Increase Program, 1954-1958 (Box 15, Folder 174)
  - Dominguez, Ricardo (Kellogg Foundation Fellow - El Salvador) - 1947-1949 Dominican Republic - 1959-1962, 1947-1962 (Box 15, Folder 175)
  - Durango, State of, 1955-1960 (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Ecuador, 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 177)
  - Egypt - 1961-1962 Ellis, D.E. (North Carolina State University) - 1962 (Box 16, Folder 178)
  - El Salvador - Central American Corn Improvement Program, 1956, 1958-1961 (Box 16, Folder 179)
  - El Salvador - Central American Corn Improvement Program, 1956, 1958-1961 (Box 16, Folder 180)
  - El Salvador - General Correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - El Salvador - General Correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 16, Folder 182)
  - El Salvador - General Correspondence, 1954-1963 (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - Embassies - 1959-1961 Enciso, Teodoro - 1962 England - 1959-1962 (Box 16, Folder 184)
  - Entomological Society of America, 1960-1962 (Box 16, Folder 185)
  - Entomology Reports, 1956-1960 (Box 16, Folder 186)
  - Equipment - Farm and General Machinery, 1954-1956 (Box 16, Folder 187)
  - Equipment - Farm and General Machinery, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 188)
  - Equipment - Farm and General Machinery, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 189)
  - Equipment - Farm and General Machinery, 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 190)
  - Equipment - Supply Companies, 1961-1962 (Box 17, Folder 191)
  - Escuela Agropecuaria de Sonora (Hermosillo), 1951-1954 (Box 17, Folder 192)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Advanced Genetics Course and Basic Food Course, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 193)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos Doctoral Process - 1958-1963 Financial Reports - 1959-1961 (Box 17, Folder 194)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - General Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - General Correspondence, 1957-1960 (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 197)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - General Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Interamerican Research and Training Center, 1959-1962 (Box 18, Folder 200)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura (Chapingo) - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Programas de Ensenanza, 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 201)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Projects, 1959-1961 (Box 18, Folder 202)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Reports (Financial), 1959-1960 (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura - Colegio de Post Graduatos - Wellhausen, E.J., 1959 (Box 18, Folder 204)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura Department of Parasitology - 1962 Equipment - 1955, 1955-1962 (Box 18, Folder 205)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura - General Correspondence, 1949-1958 (Box 18, Folder 206)
  - Escuela Nacional de Agricultura - General Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 19, Folder 207)
  - Escuela Normal Rural de Roque - (n.d.) Escuela Particular de Agricultura (Ciudad Juarez) - 1952-1957, 1961, 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 208)
  - Escuela Superior de Agricultura "Antonio Narro" - (Saltillo, Coahuila), 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 209)
  - Escuela Superior de Agricultura "Antonio Narro" - (Saltillo, Coahuila), 1952-1961 (Box 19, Folder 210)
  - Europe - 1961 Everett, Herbert L. (Cornell University) - 1960-1962 Experiment in International Living - 1959-1962 (Box 19, Folder 211)
  - FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations) - General Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations) - General Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations) - General Correspondence, 1953-1962 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - FAO - Maize Meeting (Rome-Eucarpia February 1960), 1959-1960 (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - Farmers Associations and Credit Unions, 1946-1956 (Box 20, Folder 216)
  - Fellowships (General) - 1960-1966 Fertilaid - 1954-1955 Fertilizers - 1955-1956, 1954-1966 (Box 20, Folder 217)
  - Fiji - 1962 First National Bank of New York - 1959-1961, 1959-1962 (Box 20, Folder 218)
  - Fish Pond Project - Fish Pond Sites, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 219)
  - Fish Pond Project - Fish Species, 1947-1949 (Box 20, Folder 220)
  - Fish Pond Project - Jackson, Herbert W., 1949-1951 (Box 20, Folder 221)
  - Fletcher, Donald G. (Rust Prevention Association) - 1959-1960 Florida - 1959-1962 (Box 20, Folder 222)
  - Forage Grasses and Legumes, 1953-1960 (Box 20, Folder 223)
  - Ford Foundation - Fellows, 1965-1966 (Box 20, Folder 224)